[music]
Oh,
have you heard [music] the news?
[singing]
It's probably been twisted
[music]
to keep the general population
conflicted.
Better lick your finger and turn the
[music and singing] page.
Dissect the lines that made you to
[music] rage.
Get out of one day.
Turn [music] up the volume on front page
[ __ ]
Yeah.
>> Hi, it's me, Kletchi, the baby girl, aka
Mother of London, back with a very
special episode of Front Page [ __ ]
where we turn bad news into great
conversation. This week, I'm not
actually even going through the news
with you, although I know that lots has
been happening. But what does happen is
I have the conversation with someone
extremely interesting. Yep, that's
right. Amanda Seals. So, I'm not even
going to say too much. I'm just going to
cut to it. Enjoy.
Hi everyone. [laughter]
My first interview for this brand new
podcast from Paige [ __ ] And who it
is? Who is it? the baby girl from across
the pond where every time that I will be
giving it, you are like, "Yo, you and
Amanda need to talk. You and Amanda need
to talk." Here we are. The brilliant
Amanda Seals. The brilliant Amanda Seals
is here with us people. WHAT DO YOU
ACTUALLY MEAN? [laughter]
>> I have experienced the exact same thing.
WERE LIKE,
"YOU NEED TO go to collect." [laughter]
In my mind, that's how their accent is
when they're typed in. And I'm like,
"Okay." And I have to be honest, I had
looked on your paper, you didn't follow
me. So, I was like, "Oh, I don't I know.
>> I'm I was the same." Isn't that crazy
that we're And you talked about the
autism spectrum, right? Um and and I
don't I've not been diagnosed with, you
know, I haven't gone to seek it, right?
But I'm so sensitive to I don't know if
that person likes me. So I'm not going
to Why aren't they following me? Why
aren't they following me? I'm a [ __ ]
big deal. Why aren't they following me?
I'm not going to go follow in case they
don't like me. I'm not going to go
FOLLOW ME. WHY? EVERYONE'S LIKE, BUT
[laughter] YOU'RE SO S I KNOW. We have
the same conversation in our heads.
I was like, "Well, I'm not really going
to follow if she's talking to me because
maybe she maybe she lied about
[laughter]
>> and and I was like I I just
>> No, but you know Apple cart and then but
you broke but you're the one who broke
the
>> um broke the seal.
>> Yes, the seals.
>> RIGHT. [laughter] RIGHT.
BECAUSE I SAW YOU comment and I was like
>> IT'S
[laughter]
like okay
>> all right I'm going just tell her like
yo they be saying
>> and instantly I was just like absolutely
but isn't that I think that why that is
though on a real I think it's cuz
because of the things that we talk about
we have to be so protective of ourselves
and there are so many people who
disapprove of the manner um with which
we approach the world and we approach
the things that are happening in
society. And I imagine cuz you know I've
watched your interviews and especially
with that one with um Shannon Sharp that
really aggravated me. But I watched all
of these things right and I see so many
similarities in that people don't care
for our hearts. So I'm not going to go
and put myself somewhere and then it's
like oh girl I don't actually [ __ ] with
you. I don't like you. So I just leave
people to their you know I leave people
to themselves. I I don't know what's
going to happen. So, but the
similarities are uncanny because of, you
know, the things that we say. And I love
that you say that you're a truth
translator. How did you land at that?
>> Um, I have been very fortunate to have
this long list of people who have come
into my life and been completely
pointless except for like one thing. And
I had I had somebody who was calling
themselves my manager and she was like,
"No, you're you're you're not just a
trutht teller, you're a truth
translator." And I was like, "Yeah." And
then shortly after she showed herself to
be a scam artist. So I
>> a scam translator.
>> A scam translator. So I was like, I'm
going to keep that and you go your way.
But you know, thank you. And um because
a truth translator I realize is
different than just a truth teller
because I'm not just like on a soap box
shouting it out, right?
>> So much of what is needed right now is
people being able to be brought in. Um
and they have to have um a welcome to
that that isn't necessarily always
demonstrated in the same way. Like for
some people they're like, "Oh, you're
too harsh or you're too direct, etc."
However, for some people that's what
they want, right? because that's the
teachers that they have always respected
have been direct and so they will
respond to me being direct and I feel
like the truth translation part is not
just telling you the truth but
contextualizing it right giving you a
historical reference giving you also a
moral and ethical connectivity to it
>> um you know grounding it in a context
that is bigger than just the individual
situation which happens in the United
States all the time like here
>> it's So myopic kleti it's unbelievable.
I mean it's just the simple fact that
people always say like that's happening
over there that has nothing to do with
us. And it's like literally the United
States is a parasite feeding on the
entire world. Anything that's happening
>> that we are even remotely involved with
has to do with us. Period.
>> Britain. The same with Britain. The way
that people like to push it and go, "Oh
my god, what's happening in Minnesota
right now in America is terrible. Oh my
god, WHAT HAPPENED? WHAT ABOUT WHAT'S
HAPPENING right here? Who how did
America come to be? The America that we
know, how did it come to be? Was it not
through Britain? Who were they seeking
independence from? [laughter]
And you know, to keep it above,
even though they were seeking
independence, quote unquote, they were
still really just expanding. They were
expanding the people who control the
British Empire through the banking
systems. And that's what that's what the
United States is. It's it's an expansion
of colonialism just without the sinful
name of British Empire. becomes just
colonialism and you know Britain used to
be the bully
>> that was like fourth out and then the
United States became the bully and both
both of them at this point
>> you know I saw a video kill I'm going to
send it to you because it really gave me
>> rarely do videos give me like hope I
don't know I'm hopeless I'm not hopeless
but rarely do I watch a video and I'm
like
yeah [laughter]
>> and this this stuff was like
You know, let me tell you what's
happening right now.
>> You people sold something to get white
supremacy,
>> but it wasn't real because white
supremacy isn't real. So, you got a fake
white supremacy that had a time limit on
it.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Time [laughter] is up, honey.
So, like when you talk about to a
translator, like I've been trying to
translate to people the fact that like
like
>> what we're dealing with has been
happening so much longer than just your
consciousness.
>> Yes.
And the thing is America isn't a
country, [clears throat] it's a
corporation, right? It's it's a company,
>> right? And so when you talk about
expansion, when you talk about all of
these things, this is why growth and
this is why hyperconsumerism and
capitalism is forced down our throats
because it's all it's thinking about
it's this parasitic growth to take hold
of another host, whether it's for oil,
whether it's for cobalt, whether it's
for whatever like just to take hold of
the thing and drain it dry. Yeah, people
are refusing to die. And this isn't just
this is I feel like it's the imperialist
core and we are in different parts of
the belly of the beast and and and it
was we needed to have this conversation
because we can't let the beast rest if
we're in the belly of it. We have to
keep we have to keep poking it. Make it
THROW UP. MAKE IT THROW UP.
>> MAKE [screaming] IT THROW UP. [laughter]
>> You know, and when we talk about like
the United States, right, it's just the
latest phase of imperialism. It's doing
what Europe was doing, right? Europe was
and is, you're right. Let me let me You
are so right. And is, you know, in terms
of just usurping these nations ability
to control their own resources, control
their own access to their needs, etc.
The United States just expanded that.
And so like when I hear people focus
solely on the US, I'm like you have to
understand the US is an expansion of the
claws that have already been in the mix.
People are acting as if Belgium and
France and Britain are not in Africa and
never left Africa, right? Like they act
as if that just stopped and no, it
continued and it is and has been
conspiratorial by of course other
African leaders.
You know, so it's like we've seen it now
in South Africa, in South America, in
Latin America. So there's been an entire
global movement to try to really just
reap everything from this earth without
giving back.
>> And I and and I'm trying to get folks to
to start seeing
>> the world as their responsibility, not
just their country. Mhm. Mhm. Because
the the the idea of country is false,
right? Because there are no real
borders. Like borders are made up. And
when we're talking about the Berlin
conference, especially when we look at
the continent of Africa where these men
just went and started drawing lines and
they're like this is mine, this is mine,
this is mine. What do you mean? And then
you'll have the cheat to have songs
about this land is your land, this land
is my land. No, let's all relax for
[laughter] a second. Right? And so when
we understand that that there shouldn't
be these um borders, they they shouldn't
exist in the way that we know of them.
The earth overall is all of our
responsibilities. But I feel that
ultimately people have been numbed. They
have been numbed to their own oppression
and they now they're active participants
in their own oppression. And there is no
other time that I see it more glaringly
than when I see you or me in comments.
Like I've seen you say to people like
you're marching about what's happening
but you're carrying the flag. Like
you're you're contradicting your the
flag is killing you. The very thing that
that symbol stands for is around your
neck. Like what are you not getting?
They're like not now Amanda. Not now,
Amanda. Not now. [laughter]
>> Listen.
For context, y'all, they were at a vigil
for Renee Good or Alex Freddy. And
folks, someone was standing there with a
giant American flag at the vigil,
>> which you know,
so many people have nothing to hold on
to.
>> Mhm.
>> And so this nationalism, this country
thing becomes the thing, right, that
they're identifying themselves with.
Like so many people who are outside
right now in the United States, they
think they're fighting for America,
>> right? And what is America? What is it?
>> It's literally
a a parasitic
um megalomaniacal company.
>> Yes, [laughter]
absolutely.
>> That's all it is. And and I I've been
telling people because I'm in my own
process of learning and I'm like, you
know, we're not countries like we are
banks. the places that we think our
countries are bank the the whole
Olympics and the flag and all of that
like that is really a ruse to like
attach us to something that has actually
been given to us by people who actually
don't care about us right about how many
countries don't even have their own name
Grenada where my people are from
Grenada
Grenada is not that's not the name of of
the island is the name of the island
>> and large up Morris Bishop all day every
day because what and this is the thing
anytime we get close to wanting
something and it doesn't even we're not
even saying something has to be perfect
but when we're getting close to anything
that looks like liberation here comes
some interruption and I've been to
Grenada what three times now courtesy of
the yeah courtesy of the tourism board
I've been three times and one back
[laughter]
You're not Grenadian.
>> No, [laughter]
>> I'm sending this to the tourism board.
>> You have been to Grenada three times
>> courtesy of the tourism board. The
tourism board has stood me up
>> and played with me multiple times. Not
this version, not this iteration,
>> but it is on record. Grenada, I hope
you're watching it.
>> We're going to sort it out. We're going
to sort it out. We've got people. We've
got connects. We're going to sort it
out. spice mask there and they are there
and they are about the people and so
hopefully they will bring both of us
back.
>> No, they have to. I'm hoping fingers
crossed so to the people that know get
us both. you need us both in Grenada at
the same time. and he's looking at um
what um is it Dick and Mitchell what
he's doing now as um prime minister of
Grenada and again wait even like I look
at what we've had previous or what I've
learned about previously in previous
like governments and things like that
and I'm like okay you're starting to
talk about some things however I do find
that sometimes it can be a bit
condescending to the people
it's it's
but wouldn't you say when it comes to
someone like him, they have to start
somewhere.
>> No,
>> no,
>> no. When where we've had someone like
Morris Bishop already.
>> Well, also, you know, there's just a lot
of romanticism around Maurice Bishop and
the movements, etc. And the Caribbean,
right? Like when we look at the
Caribbean, I think that we forget that
the Caribbean is what I consider to be
the Africa of the Western Hemisphere. It
is a consortium of black islands, mostly
black people that have been colonized in
soft power and hard power ways, right?
So you have like St. Croy that are a
part of the US uh version. How right?
You have places like Martin which are
still French, you know, and will Dutch
>> and then you have places like Grenada,
>> right? Then you have places like Grenada
and Jamaica, right? So like Jamaica
looks independent but it is still owned
by Britain. So they don't have any
control of their beaches. You look at a
place like Grenada and it seems like
okay Grenada is independent but at the
end of the day Grenada has a medical
school that essentially is a huge part
of our entire um economy and is largely
supported by Americans. That's soft
power. Instead of having a military
base, they had a medical school. And it
was that medical school that they used
as the reason to invade in [laughter]
>> was it 86?
Yeah.
>> 83.
>> So they literally said, "Oh, well, we
have to invade because we have American
medical students in the island and you
are becoming communist and that's a
danger to our people." So they use these
factions, you know, then they'll do
things like putting uh Kamla in power in
Trinidad, right? The prime minister of
Trinidad is uh I forgot her last name
but her first name is Kamla but she won
her first election I think it was like
2010 maybe and she was put in power with
the help of of Cambridge Analytica.
Cambridge Analytica, for those who don't
know, is the very
um unethical data processing analytical
company that has Steve Bannon, who is
Trump's right-hand man, on the board,
and that absolutely infringes upon
elections all over the world. and and
Mark Zuckerberg had to admit to that
that that that did he had to admit to
that that that did happen through
Cambridge Analytica data to Cambridge
Analytica. So like that. So now when you
see her in position again and you see
her being like we love the United
States, we love Donald Trump, you
understand, oh this has been a process
in, you know, in in um this has been in
process and the the the Caribbean has
Caraccom which you know, similar to um
like organized countries in in Africa.
I'm I'm blanking right now.
>> It looks on the surface like look at us.
>> Yeah. Y
>> coming together to work with each other
when in actuality it ends up being we
have
>> allowed you all to come together so that
we can now
>> take control you from here. Yeah. We can
control you from here. And this is what
makes it sad. And then people obviously
will talk about Ibrahim Trayor and they
will talk about Bikina Faso and Mali and
Chad and all the things that are being
done there. But to me that worries me
because they're of their anti-LGBTQ
stance.
>> I mean Yes.
>> Right.
Right. So whilst it's just like we can't
say that we are taking out the clause of
imperialist um you know white
supremacist hetropatriarchy out of our
systems while still wanting to propagate
something that is still harmful to
marginalized folk, right?
>> Yes.
>> And but I still I still I still get like
we want to get our resources and have
you know autonomy and agency over our
resources.
Well, I think this is when we end up
having to kind of do the dance of grace,
right? Because ultimately they are still
the subject of that same imperialism,
right? So,
>> it's like, okay, um that's wrong, y'all.
And and we need you to address that, but
I can't throw away the whole baby with
the bath water. Um because the B I'm
hoping that in the process of throwing
away the bath water, we will be able to
address the baby. Um whereas prior they
weren't even trying to throw away the
bath water like they were they were
swimming in that we love the bath water.
I'm sitting in it.
>> It's brown. It's nasty. It's murky. But
I'm loving it here. It's it's gray. This
I'm h you know that that Yeah, I'M
LOVING IT. [laughter]
I MEAN, YOU KNOW, I think it's the
reality is that when people talk about
purity politics, um, they're talking
about like we can't really hold people
accountable for sending money to a
genocide. I mean, that's just not
something we can do
and [laughter]
and and it's being applied to people who
are actually in power position, right?
Um,
as much as I 100% agree with you about
the anti-LGBTQ
stance in Bkina Faso, Mali and Nair, I
also understand
that
>> that is the version of we have to start
somewhere that I feel like I have to
acknowledge
>> that you can that you can get. That's
it. And for me, that's why it works both
ways. Cuz I'm I have to think if I'm
going to say, you know what, Ibrahim and
all of them man, I'm going to give you a
bllye because of this particular, but
I'm hoping that we can fix it. I'm also
looking at other places and going I you
still have a lot of work to do, but
let's see where you're going with this.
I want to see where you're going with
this. It's that grace that you speak of
that I am not in that position of power.
I don't know what the hell I'd be doing.
People, YOU MIGHT WE YOU'D BE ON A
PODCAST WITH SOMEBODY else dra dragging
the hell out of me. I don't know what
I'd be doing, but I'm trying to figure
something out. And I'm definitely not
taking money from Apac, you know. I'm
I'm not doing all of it. I'm not taking
money in the UK version, Friends of
Israel. I'm not trying to take money
from them lot. But it it does make it
really really challenging. But we've got
to do something. And I just want I I'm
not into, oh, I just need to see more
women and I need to see more things. I
just need people to start thinking or
moving from their soul. So, not even on
a woo woo spiritual vibe, but it's what
you were saying with from about Earth.
Why? Why are we doing this? How can we
wait? So, we're on a rock hurtling
through space. Hurtling through space.
We don't know where we're going. What's
going to happen? We're not taking in
that phenomena that we are living beings
on a hurtling rock and we're happening
to be here. But instead, we're going,
you know what? War, war, pedophilia,
taxes. That's what I like. That's what I
want to push forward. and we're all
going on and we're going along with it
as if it's sane, as if it's a normal
thing to want to do. And I don't know
how we break away from that.
>> So, in my [sighs]
humble opinion,
>> you're right.
Um,
[laughter]
part of what is so necessary to convince
people of is their power beyond what
they're given.
>> Oh yeah.
>> So we are we have become beings that
only consider power to be something that
is given to us
>> external to oneself. Yeah. Yeah.
>> And rel religiosity is also a a pillar
of this.
>> And so that has been ingrained to keep a
populace able to be controlled because
they never fully trust themselves.
>> They never fully believe in their own
power. And part of that is by
disconnecting them from earth because
you know that pride is pride. Yeah.
>> You understand that the earth is
powerful. And I don't mean that even
like you said in a woo way. The earth is
literally powerful. Like it has minerals
and magnetism and
all of those things. [laughter]
>> Like it it it it is a the earth has a
heartbeat because it is constantly
generating and emitting energy, right?
So anything that has energy and emits
energy has a certain level of power.
That's just what it is. We as humans are
constantly giving off energy. We know
that because when someone walks in the
room and you're like, "Oo, I ain't like
that energy." And that vibration.
>> Yeah.
>> So I'm trying to
In my radicalism, in my decolonization
work, I'm trying to connect people back
to looking and learning with not just
minds, but with their hearts as well. So
much of what we're learning is about
just learning facts, learning timelines,
learning dates, learning,
>> but we're not integrating exactly how
that actually connects to the heart and
the soul and the existence. I grew up
with teachers that were doing that work
in the classroom. Like that was a part
of how they taught. This happened and it
was not good because XYZ. DID YOU LIKE
WHEN THIS HAPPENED? What do you think
about this? We're not taught in class,
in school, on television, in movies. We
are not taught to not only think
critically. We are also not taught to
think principally. We're not taught to
think ethically. And we don't have we
act as if there isn't a base for that.
when when nature really is, you know, a
base for that. Like you can look at the
way
>> it's a blueprint
>> and find many answers. I saw I saw um I
talked to my brother because I was
appreciative of his story, but I saw
this white man
>> telling a story the other day, this
physician about bonobos. Do you know
what bonobos are?
>> It's a matriarchal vibe. And then they
saw one abuse a child and they beat the
[ __ ] out of they beat the
Good.
>> And it's the first ever recorded murder
by Bonobos
>> in years. That That's what they were
saying. Yeah. They've never seen it. But
the in the time that they have been
watching this specific group that
they've never seen anything like it.
It's never been anywhere. And also I
found when I saw that what was so
important was the rest stood back cuz
they knew it's
done.
>> They weren't in the comments saying,
"You guys, let's be nonviolent."
>> No. And at the same time, let's raise
our bonobo ch our bonobo children better
so they don't end up in situations where
they can be beaten or they can be
treated in this way. What was the bonobo
child wearing? What was what we
is that ludicrous? Yes, we're talking
about primates that we've got 98% um in
terms of gen genetics, we're 98% we
>> are family and them man can look at
what's happening and say hey that's
wrong and it's the fact that it was the
three female bonobos that got together
and killed him. Yes. Yes. It's a rap.
>> Yeah. [laughter] Not and for the let me
know.
>> Right. But then we'll be online or we'll
be wherever we are calling out things.
We're not beating an a male bonobo to
death, but we're just calling out. We're
just pointing out the things that are
happening in society and they're like,
"You shouldn't be doing that. That is so
wrong. Why are you so angry all of the
time?" Oh, okay. All right. Well, we
should just all sit around and just
watch then. But this is what I wanted to
ask you about, though, because I don't
think people ask you enough. They don't
give you space e any of us e either of
us space for this. How do you move? How
do you navigate loneliness?
>> I really don't get lonely anymore.
>> I um
I was forced to find out how to get
through that by being ostracized. Like
in 2024,
I was
essentially like kicked out of black
media. Um, there was an entire smear
campaign that was launched that was
Amanda Seals is unlikable. And so
articles
popped up on like Essence and Black
Enterprise and the Grio and the Root.
And this then became the pylon of, you
know, and whether or not it's bots or
people combined, it still becomes
something we feel, right? And people
saying like, you know, she's this and
she's that. And it was never people I
know, by the way. That was the always
fascinating part. It was never people I
know, but it's still an energy that's
coming towards you that really started
to bring out my shadows and my
self-doubt and my self-hatred. And I had
to really face what is this like where
why is it when these people who I know
don't know me are saying things about me
that I know to be skewed and to be, you
know, riddled with um jealousy and
unintellectualism, etc., etc. Why am I
taking this to heart? Well, it's because
it's grounded in a real thing, which is
me feeling like I'm not understood and
me really desiring this understanding to
feel like I'm at home.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> And
I was really forced, Kletchi, to go on a
journey
>> of finding my own inner understanding
>> that
relied far less. I'm not going to say
that I still don't care, but I mean
percentage of 50/50 to like 10%. You
know, and and being a part of this
internet world is also its own, you
know, that's its own version of harm on
you not being able to adjust in that
way. And so there was two phases. I was
with somebody for three years. We broke
up in 2023.
And upon that breakup,
I really had to ask myself like
What do you really want?
>> Like what were you getting from this
person that [laughter]
that you can't get from yourself?
>> And I had to have that same conversation
about me and my mother.
>> What are you getting from this person
that you're not getting from yourself? I
had to have that same conversation about
the friends that I had around me. What
are you getting from these people that
you're not getting from yourself? But
when I was really, really, really,
really honest, it ended up coming down
to ego stroking.
>> Um, it ended, and listen, ego stroking
can be necessary. Jordie, please. We're
doing a podcast.
>> Hey, Jordy. Babe,
[laughter]
>> don't get me wrong, like you do need to
be built up. Like, we're in a world
that's like beating you down all the
time. However, sometimes
>> it's just not helpful to you and it's
it's blinding you. It's giving you a
blind spot.
um to your own ability to connect to
self. And when
when October 7th took place, um so much
of what I had thought was the truth
became completely eradicated. The veil
was completely removed. So it was like
these three things happening, boom,
boom, boom, left me in a a desert.
>> Mhm. Mhm.
>> And you when you know I had to like find
my way
>> to something real
>> with nothing around me except me.
>> And that became
>> getting grounded in spirituality.
>> That became getting grounded in um
really just my art. coming back to my
creativity and my art as a true source
of power that doesn't have to be uh
necessarily put out there for people. It
really can just be a way to funnel my my
my overwhelming emotions that I have all
the time into something of value. And
really learning that I was autistic was
a huge awakening because it released me
from
the shame that I feel caused the
loneliness. Because the loneliness for
me came from feeling misunderstood.
>> Yes.
>> Yep.
>> So once I began
to understand myself and the
spirituality and all those things and
then the autism was the final like door
opening to Narnia because it clarified
not only the present but the past.
>> Yeah.
>> It alleviated me of this feeling like
why can't I just be someone people like?
Why can't I just be normal? Right? And
when you talking about that, it hits
somewhere deep in me because I would
often say to those close to me, I I I
don't get what it is. Like why why am I
so misunderstood? I'll hear some people
describe me and I'll be like, Ra, SHE'S
A [ __ ] LIKE I [laughter] LIKE BUT
THAT'S I
>> LIKE I'm not leading with that.
>> Yeah, that's not
>> like I didn't go into that situation to
be a [ __ ] Like so how did that get
received? How did that? And all I did
was say, "Hey, the sky is blue." Or,
"Hey, the color in this room is green."
I just said what I
>> have said happy birthday to someone and
they said, "Don't tell me what to do.
[laughter]
>> I don't want to be happy on my birthday.
I don't need you telling me policing my
like." So, you know, the way that we
verbalize things, the way that we speak
is also so direct. We have
>> we have a deep voice. We have
conviction.
>> We have conviction. We don't we but we
but even aside from passion, WE KNOW
WHAT we're talking about.
>> But how dare you? because I'm looking at
it and I you know I'm I don't want to
dwell on it per se, but even seeing that
smear campaign happen against you at the
time. You'd be surprised to know that
yeah, you are somebody that we can say
specializes in knowing about
African-Amean history, but they that
wasn't how it was RIGHT HERE,
>> RIGHT? BUT [laughter] THAT'S NOT that's
not how people are leading with it. It's
just oh, she just she's just like that
and she and you know what? for all of
the nuances around colorism. I also
think that the reason that certain
things could go ahead and like she
thinks she's so she thinks too much of
it's because you're light-kinned. So it
was just like
>> I know people watch and be like what are
you saying? Are you saying re reverse
colorism? I never [ __ ] said that. But
what I am saying is that there are
certain [laughter]
>> I never [ __ ] said that.
>> BUT IT'S TRUE,
>> RIGHT? I'm also pretty
>> a cutie.
A cutie. A painting.
So, IT'S JUST LIKE, HOW DARE YOU?
[laughter]
>> HOW DARE YOU?
>> A PAINTING. Come on. Come on.
>> IT'S LIKE, HOW dare you?
>> How dare you be attractive? How dare you
have cute style? How dare you take care
of yourself and give us looks and also
give us insight and observ observations
that are salient that are incisive that
are irreverent because you're not bowing
down every time somebody says to you you
should like this person. Even when I've
seen you talk with people and really try
to call them in and say, "Hey guys, even
Kamla Harris, even Kamla Harris, I'm
tired of you lot saying, "Oh, well, if
y'all have just voted for for Kamla, if
y'all
>> [laughter]
>> If y'all are just giving Jasmine
Crockett a chance, which you're not
going to do, I'm absolutely going to do
that. I'm absolutely going to hold every
entity that represents the institution,
every oppressive governmental force. I'm
going to hold them to task and you
aren't going to tell me that because
that they've got a [ __ ] I should calm
down. No,
>> no. Because anybody can be an agent of
white supremacy. What do you mean? And I
am more honestly I am more critical of
black folks who are me who are
representing it because we know that
they are more effective agents. We have
seen this over and over and over and
over again. At what point do we say okay
y'all have shown us how you work. Let's
actually respond to that with insight
and acuteness and acuity. Okay. They be
infiltrating. So now I got to make sure
everybody who comes through here and
then they'll say, "Well, who are you TO
DO THAT?" FIND SOMEBODY who has a proven
track record. That's what I am.
I have made it my business to be very
out here and loud all the time about
everything. So you don't even have any
secrecy to accuse me of. There's really
been a commitment to saying, "Okay, I'm
doing this now. You know what? I learned
this, so I'm not rocking with that no
more. I'm learning this now. Hey, I'm
putting you guys onto this. Hey, I'm
with these people. Like, people have
watched me ki go from being a child
actor to a full radical leftist who has
no corporate support
>> whatsoever. I am fully 100% supported by
the people in the mirror.
[laughter]
>> It's literally just Patreon
subscriptions and support of my art and
my offerings that I give on
amandexports.com.
That's it. I wrote a book. What would
the ancestors say is my latest book?
That's literally how I am funding. And
when people SAY LIKE, "WELL, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?" I just did an entire book
tour that I funded because sent me and
my security guard out to all these
cities to do talks with folks. And the
And by the way, the talks were free.
People
were free. You could buy a book or not
buy a book a book.
>> Wow.
>> So like we have to to consider
>> the fact that there are people who are
going to be placed in our way.
>> And when you look at us as those people,
you're missing
>> the learning. And that's always Yeah,
that was always going to be the point
though. We would look like the
antagonist. Well, you know, whatever. We
would look like the ones that you're
meant to fear. And what are you fearing
in us? The fact that we are moving
confidently towards our own liberation
and we're reclaiming ourselves. what it
is to be um sovereign in this life for
ourselves and hold ourselves accountable
because at the same time that they've
watched us grow they've seen us do these
things made mistakes along the way but
I've owned that always unlearning always
unlearning that yeah I didn't quite get
that right so you know what I did I went
away and I started I went and did more
research so I could show up better not
just for myself but for us all and
literally they will say to you like you
said what have you been doing I built a
children's home in Nigeria in Lagos
Nigeria me and my um took my money from
all of these speaking engagements
brick by brick built the children's home
in Lagos. Why? Because somebody needs to
many people need to disrupt the
orphanage industrial complex that is
used as a facade for for child
trafficking.
>> There are so many ways in which we are
losing the children. We are losing the
babs
>> and we're not even aware because of
false altruism that oh they're doing
good, they're doing good. How many
things have we how many ways have we
been oppressed and subjugated cuz we've
been told that these people are doing
good in some way and we've gone with it.
>> It's crazy.
>> We want we want to believe they're good
so bad so that we can actually be
alleviated of the responsibility of
saving ourselves,
>> right? And somebody's going to do it.
And now I've said I've seen an
exponential uptick in people going back
to organized religion. Why? Because it's
like let somebody tell me what to do and
Sky Daddy's going to fix it. Sky Daddy's
going to come down and Sky Daddy's going
to Sky Daddy whatever you want to
believe your the responsibility is still
ours to get on with fixing whatever this
is and being open. I think what
spirituality has taught me I don't know
if it's been the same for you is being
okay with destruction being okay with
something toppling down so we can start
again. Meanwhile, people are trying to
keep the system, keep the structure, the
framework erect that is resting on the
backs of marginalized folk, but they
want to keep it erect, but they're
telling you somehow we're going to we're
going to change. We're fighting for
America. This is what I mean.
>> This is what I mean when people say we
need to when you're talking about Kla
Harris and Jasmine Crockett, they
represent exactly what you just
described. They are the establishment
built on the backs. And as and people
get mad at me.
>> I actually had a really dope
conversation with Scholola Moss about
electoral politics and she was saying
that she still believes in it and I was
like, you know, I don't because it has
shown over and over again that it really
is just a tool of pacification and that
it doesn't actually lead us to be able
to make legitimate change because it is
controlled so stringently by the powers
that be. Now they can rig it
>> and we get and I mean I mean they've
been rigging it because ultimately in
the states the electoral college has
always made this a rigged thing.
>> Yeah. We've got first pass the post
here. We've got all of that politics.
Yeah.
>> If you have a company,
>> are you if you have a company and you
have a history of exploiting the people
that work for your company,
>> are you going to then give them the
power to vote for who runs the company?
>> Absolutely not.
So like nonsense is watching people say
I'm going to run for for Senate and then
everyone like you said running to them
the same way they're running to their
pastor to be like okay you're going to
save us. You're going to save us. Let me
give you some of my money. Let me give
you my time. They don't have the power
to
>> they don't have the power to. All
they're doing is holding up the power.
They're profiting power. BUT I WANTED to
ask you this actually. Sorry to
interrupt. I wanted to ask you this
because I'm seeing a lot of celebrities,
the ones that usually stay quiet about
every [ __ ] thing. Now they're talking
about, you know, ice out, ice out, and
then now they're saying, "What you need
to do is call your senator. Call your
senator." And I'm like, "What?" Again,
help me, right? Help me understand,
Amanda. So, when you call said senator,
what is going to happen? because you're
still trying to use the master's tools
to dismantle the master's house, and I
don't get that. Or am I just being
overly critical? Can these senators do
something?
>> First of all, your percentage of
incorrectness is incredibly low. So, you
are not being overcritical. Um,
[laughter]
>> this comes back to what you were saying
about people looking at these white
folks coming in and doing good and
wanting to that they're doing good.
How the political structure has become
in the United States. Folks don't look
at politicians as someone to question.
They look at them as so it continues
that mind state to tell them if you call
them and you ask them and you demand of
them they're going to do the right
thing. There is no [screaming] history,
no empirical proof that is substantial
enough to suggest that that even makes
sense because what it would mean is that
these politicians are in position
because of you and that is the trick.
Politicians in the United States,
particularly at the electoral level, so
Congress, meaning the House of
Representatives and senators, they are
elected quote unquote by the vote of the
people. However, everybody knows that it
is lobbyists. It is the corporations
that are by and large funding their
campaigns. They are the ones determining
who gets in position. They are the ones
determine how the Supreme Court is going
to vote on things. It is a completely
deeply corrupted system.
>> Yes.
>> 100%. So to tell people if you just call
them
>> just call them call them.
>> They're they're going to listen to you.
First of all, they don't even answer the
damn phone. Second of all, there isn't
any reason for them to listen to you.
And that's really what I'm trying to get
people to understand. It doesn't behoove
them to listen to you. Like, you're not
changing their course. These are people
who have not come into politics to be
public servants. They have come into
politics to get money and to look
famous.
>> I tell people DC is the same as
Hollywood. Instead of script, their
speeches, they love a suit. They love a
They love a suit and tie, but podcast.
>> Oh, they love a podcast
and and you know, just telling us that
we're just getting it wrong because
look, you can't change things from
outside the room. You have to be in
these rooms to change.
>> So, everything says that and I'm like,
but you're getting in the room and
you're not communicating with anyone
outside, you know, like you afterwards.
You're in the room now with your chair
that I've got to seat at the table. YOUR
YOUR CHAIR HAS THREE LEGS and it's
wobbly. It's wobbly even. And then the
seat that you have at the table, they're
barely passing water over to your side
or your end of the table. You're eating
crumbs and you're trying to convince us
that you did something great, that you
did something good
>> because you're there. And that is a huge
issue with black folks in the United
States is that we have been trained to
believe that just being there is
advancement. It is progression. And I
refuse to settle for that crumb.
>> Yeah. And it's there are other means.
You can just not go to that table. You
can just understand that the there
shouldn't have been a table in that way
in the first place. The feast of life
was for all of us. It has always been
for all of us. It has been hoarded. So
you are amongst hoarders is what's
happened. I don't want to be amongst
hoarders.
>> If you're not showing up to the table
with an axe,
>> oh,
>> I don't care that you're there.
>> What does it mean for me? So we we're
we're using corporate language and we're
just becoming that when we're not moving
anything forward. And so it's I just
find it truly fascinating. But then how
do you think that Mamani differs from
that?
>> I don't know yet.
>> Okay.
I don't know yet. There hasn't been
enough consistency for me to believe
him. So um he's definitely walking the
line. Yeah,
>> he is absolutely I think on a basic
level Mi is trying to like do what
Democrats so often do, which is nice
things in dark places. like they'll do
some nice things, but the thing about it
is that they're never able to to do
things that last because their changes
are always based on regime and
>> they're not actually system changes,
right? They're built into the actual
infrastructure because the
infrastructure is controlled by Zionist
and
>> are in no way wanting people to have uh
like like um what's the word I'm looking
for? Abundance.
>> No. Yeah.
>> Zionism is actively about we want there
to be only a few people that have the
things and we want everyone else to be
struggling and we like it.
>> Yeah.
We like off of that. Like that's our
vibe.
>> It's sick.
>> It's very sick. And how have you found,
you know, because we're similar in the
way that we're self-produced. I've got
my website, my members area where I do
all of my things from, you know, because
I'm not expecting to be invited to the
things, you know, booked to do certain
things because of the way that I call
things out. So, we have to make sure
that we are self- sustained in order to
do the work that we do. And ultimately,
in that sense, that we can't be bought,
right? because if these brands are
giving us things, they're going to
expect us to shut up to have the things.
And I'm like, you know what? I love
yapping too much. You know, I love
yapping too much. I wake up and I'm
like, what can I tell the PEOPLE TODAY?
[laughter] WHAT HAVE I DISCOVERED TODAY?
LIKE I I think through the, you know,
whether it's the IAS, whether it's this,
I've woken up to really feeling life.
And it's painful at a lot of points, but
I don't ever want to stop feeling
whatever this is. I never want to stop
feeling it because at least I'm
understanding that this is what it is to
be alive to see somebody else's pain and
and feel it as your pain and to want to
do whatever is in your power to let
people know that this isn't right and
this must stop. Like it's how how fun is
it to go and carry a shiny shoe in a bag
when you know that people are being
killed in Congo? Like it it doesn't I
can't do that.
>> I can't believe I can't believe we
thought either of us didn't like each
other. I love you so much. [laughter]
>> I like you a lot. Look at this. And hey,
anybody who's listening, we want to do
this in person. So, as long as you're
not Zai, can you bring the things? Bring
the venue. [laughter]
Bring the venue. Bring the things.
>> I need to get out of the US bubble.
>> Um, all of us need to get out of our
bubbles.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, that's been by design. that
we've been put in these bubbles and then
you know it's it's I say this not not
lightly like it's trippy that both of us
as strong voices as we are have been so
um traumatized
that we kept ourselves in our bubbles
from each other when the truth is we
have to be aligned right like we have to
be a part of a global network of folks
that have not just courage but what you
just said, which is we have a
willingness to lean into our
sensitivity, to not run it, but to
alchemize it. And that's what I'm trying
to in folks. Your emotions and your
sensitivity are not something to run
from. They can actually be the thing
that leads you to the liberation that
you really actually do seek, but that
you're afraid of cuz you're afraid of
what you're going to have to do. And
listen, it's you can't if our
sensitivities if our sensitivities
weren't so powerful that corporations
wouldn't spend such a large amount of
money trying to numb it, marketing to us
to give us so many distractions so we
don't feel because to feel is to be
alive and we need to be doing something.
And and you're right, it's that word
that you use especially is about being
so traumatized by where we are and the
things that we've seen that's like, oh,
I'm I don't know. I don't know what it's
going to be like over there. And I was
saying it in my members area as well. I
said, I don't like the fact that I don't
trust like I don't I'm I'm scared now
because so you people just do weird
things, especially as you said around
management, agents, all of these things.
And initially they make it out like,
"Oh, I love your voice. I love that
you're so outspoken. I love this. I love
that." And then you just start seeing
that essentially what looks like
sabotage and and nobody having your back
with these with you know with these
people and then they'll be telling you
about book sales this that and the
other. Well, I don't know how you expect
me to push my book when people are dying
and people are experiencing various
types of genocide but actually jump
online and say, "Hey guys, the paperback
version is out." Like what? What? Well,
I actually bought my I had a memoir that
was supposed to come out last year on
Simon and Schustster and I bought it
back from them.
>> Yeah,
>> I bought it back. I um
>> I think about that check a lot. But I
>> I hear it. I hear it. I hear it.
[laughter]
>> You know, but it's it's a version of
buying your freedom. You know, I wrote
this memoir. It was 150,000 words. And
then my editor was like, "Oh, I'm going
on maternity leave." Which I just
thought meant like you're going to go
have the baby. No, she was like, "I'm
not going to be available like at all."
And I'm like, "We are reading a book
together. You live 6 minutes away from
me." Long story short, I I finally get
around to her notes and it's revealed in
her notes that she's a Zionist and I've
known this woman for seven years, but
she reveals, you know, she's a and she
doesn't like me.
>> Oh, she doesn't like me. [laughter] Like
when I'm reading the edit, I'm like
>> Samantha does not like me.
>> Cuz none of the edits are about the
actual construction or the grammar
choices.
>> How dare you?
>> How dare you? I made a sentence where I
said, "Of course they would come and
smear campaign me. I had 2.3 million
followers. I was on HBO and I'm bonafide
brilliant." and she wrote, "How are we
measuring brilliance?"
>> Oh my [laughter] god.
>> Not that you aren't, but it seems
contradictory
to name two facts and an opinion to
support your theory. [laughter]
>> So, so pray tell, who is going to be the
arbiter of my said brilliance if not
myself? Who the hell is going to come
along and tell me that I'm brilliant if
not me? I'm telling you I'm brilliant.
You didn't give me the book deal without
me bring you gave me [laughter] not
say
>> listen I had to sage her out.
>> That is diabolical.
>> Diabolical. Then she sets it sets me up
with another editor
who a week after I turn in my book
says,
>> "Yeah, so you wrote 150,000 words, but
your contract actually only asks for
75,000 words." And so can you cut um
75,000 words? Like are there chapters
that you're just not married to?
[laughter]
>> I'm not the phone. I have to cut the
phone. I have to cut the phone.
>> We go together real bad. me and those me
and those 75 extra 75,000 words we go
together real bad
>> real bad
>> and you know and it was like I started
to get pushed in this corner collection
of like well if you want the book to
come out then you have to do this you
have to do it in this time frame and
that and then I realized I'm writing a
memoir and I'm working for somebody else
how how how is this a situation where I
am now under the gun for these people
and it's my story and I'm under the gun
to make my story fit into their
contract. Like this doesn't even make
sense.
>> The very reality of what we're doing,
our expansive natures, our expansive
beings, the beings that we are being
folded and crunched and crushed into
society's expectations, especially
through publications or publishing. And
I've noticed that that a way to go and
silence or or distract people who are
experiencing their own radicalization
and waking up to what life is is to give
them a book deal. Because then it's
like, okay, you go and focus over there.
you've got all that writing to do and
then they can chip away at our
confidence by being like, "Oh, you
didn't write that properly and you
didn't do that and you've got this and
you've got that and you've got to meet
these metrics." And so without even
realizing it, we start to kind of round
ourselves off at the edges cuz we want
to be and and if you're if we're
anything alike, my mind is now like I
need this book to do well. Them man got
bestsellers. They those lot over there,
they got bestellers. I need to and now
I'm distracted. Now I'm distracted.
>> What happened to me was I I'm very
fortunate that I have one person that I
work with who we are squad and I know
that she has my best interest at heart,
right? And but by the way y'all, this is
my home girl. Like this wasn't an agent.
This wasn't a manager. This was a home
girl. And over time, we just started
working together in different ways and
it's, you know, blossomed into a real
dope understanding. And we had a
conversation about like what is it? what
does it mean to do this book?
>> And I said, well, let's approach this
from an abundance mindset. So, if I do
the book with them
and it comes out in February, well,
that's Black History Month, so it'll be
more push. Um, I'll do press. And then I
stopped in my tracks and I was like,
"But wait, press
>> that means I'm gonna have to go on all
these shows that I don't even [ __ ] with
>> people ask questions.
I don't want to go on Good Morning
America." Like, I did all of that. I did
it. I did it. I don't respect any of
these places anymore. And now I'm going
to all of a sudden because I have a
book, I'm going to go go to those
places. Like you look a mess, Amanda.
And then Kletchi, an eagle started
flying towards my house. I [ __ ] you not.
I'm literally looking out the window. An
eagle flies towards my house. And I'm
like, so I do what anyone would do. And
I ran up and I got my pocket guide to
spirit animals. And
I looked up eagle [laughter]
naturally.
>> Exactly what we were doing to [laughter]
>> What does this mean? It said
this is a sign that you need to zoom out
and look at your life from a deeper
perspective. You need to commune with
the divine in regards to your
creativity. So, you know, sometimes I
know people are like it's all generic.
No, because not everybody is operating
in a creative space. That was a very
specific message that said you need and
the zoom out was me realizing
exactly what you just described. If I go
down this road any further, I am making
myself smaller.
>> And I'm on the cover of this book
smiling, looking up like I did it. While
people are being genocided,
>> while people are being kidnapped. Yeah.
Like I'm over here talking about my
journey to myself and my instead of
having a midlife crisis, I had a midlife
awakening. So I'm supposed to come out
here and talk about this while people
are literally being snatched out of
preschools.
>> Yeah.
>> I look a mess because it neutralizes us.
It neutralizes us cuz we've got to go
and push that book. So it's like, oh
well, if I now post this on the
timeline, then I'm going to straight
after follow it with this. Then I had to
say to myself, who gives a heck? Who
gives an actual flying [ __ ]
>> RIGHT? YOU WERE ABOUT TO science it out
like if I do this then if I do this and
it balances. Look at the math that
you're doing to have to fit into their
metric
>> for what?
>> It's and you know what we're very very
very very fortunate because
>> my home girl was telling me yesterday
she was like you know she has these two
friends who are super stressed right
now. They're in corporate and they're
super stressed and they're looking to
her and they're like
>> you've never really been stressed even
when you was in corporate like what that
what's that about? And she told them
because I am not making choices in my
life responding to social norms.
>> Yeah.
>> The social norms are meant to keep us
stressed.
>> Yeah.
And she was like, "It's not to say that
there isn't a ven diagram where
sometimes a social norm makes sense for
me, but she was like, the fact that you
are stressing about paying for this
house that you bought right before you
got fired or laid off?
>> What made you buy this house?
>> What made you
>> Who are we doing it for? Who it's all
made up. Who are we doing it for?"
And I was in LA. And it wasn't until I
left LA and I moved back east to a
suburb that is a village that is nature.
Like deer are casually around me that I
got to disconnect and decompress from
the constant state of competition. Ki
this is the first time in my life that
my social network is not born from
competition. It's not born from us being
in the same industry or us playing the
same sport or us doing the same
creativity. It [laughter] is it's it's
game changing. Like my friends here are
um a librarian,
an astrologologist.
>> Oh my god.
>> A nurse,
a black futurist.
Um, [laughter] like a a woman who
literally goes into nonprofits just to
show them that they're full of [ __ ]
Like these are the people in my circle,
>> you know, and I've never experienced
this level of clarity of self in my
life. And it shows because all of them
>> really,
>> it shows. And I think, you know, when we
were saying, "Oh, why hadn't we
connected sooner?" I feel like we were
both individually still doing the work
that we needed to do, the coming home to
self. And I it's not it's not a final
journey. It's not final destination, but
you know, we're still figuring it out.
It's this journey, but now it's like,
oh, we can continue like we we've been
doing the necessary things so we can
show up and really see each other. So,
you're to me glowing across the screen.
I recognize that. I recognize that. And
I'm like, yes, my G. Yes. Yes. And we
this this isn't meant to take us out.
We're told it should. doing this work is
meant to make you die early of some kind
of disease or destitute, poor, whatever
it we're told that. And yet here we are
defying even that that I'm going to say
what I see. I'm going to name the devils
that I see and nobody is going to stop
me doing that and I'm still going to
have a life that feels somewhat like
peace. It is possible. That's the part
people are always like, "How are you
pouring into yourself?" I'm like, "I
live in peace because I'm saying the
things I'm saying. If I wasn't speaking
the way I speak, I would not be in
peace.
>> Yeah.
>> I would actually be riddled with anxiety
because I know that I'm not living in my
true self and I know that I'm being a
bystander to absolute [ __ ]
>> Yes, exactly, guys. Front page [ __ ]
in this story. [laughter]
>> Come on. You know you got the skill set.
[laughter]
So,
>> I just gave her a promo right there.
Right there. Boom.
[laughter]
But even what you were saying about the
eagle, eagles are massive.
>> They are massive. And so and even the So
when you said that, the image that came
to my mind was you're also being
reminded of your size. You're not a
small girl. You're not No, you're not a
little girl out here.
>> My cleaning woman, Gloria, reminded me
of this the other day because Gloria
said, "Amanda,
you have a lot of things." [laughter]
And I was like, Gloria, because I'm a
lot of person, [laughter]
>> you are Jay
>> on various interests. I want to go back
TO TAP DANCING. I'M LEARNING TO PLAY THE
GUITAR. NOW I THINK I want to learn the
saxophone and I want to learn another
language.
>> I woke up this morning and did a
trampoline workout. I I assembled a mini
trampoline this morning and did a
trampoline workout on live on Patreon
because I have committed myself for the
last 3 weeks. I have committed myself to
every 20 minutes every day. Every day I
have to do 20 minutes of some type of
movement because I believe I've come to
believe my soul my my soul is in this
body. This body is is an extension of
the earth.
>> In order for my soul, which powers this
body, to be able to really grow and
expand and exist in its full purpose, it
needs to be housed
>> in a cellular structure that is cared
for.
>> Yes. And we are living in systems that
actively do not teach us to do that, do
not give us the ability to do that,
don't give us time to do that, right?
Don't give us the food to do that.
>> And everything gets bastardized.
Everything gets corrupted. So something
that's meant to be about quote unquote
wellness, every it's been commodified.
It's been repackaged and it being made
this elitist thing or being used as a
way to create some kind of societal
strata that doesn't need to be there. I
say all the time when people are like,
"Oh, why do you run so much? Why do you
go gym? Why do you do Muay Thai? I do
all of these things because it is to pay
reverence to my body. This vessel that
allows me to move through this earth and
go through whatever soul lessons that I
decided I wanted to learn this time
round on this iteration of Earth or this
iteration of reality. I must honor this
vessel and also prepare this vessel
because [ __ ] around and find out like
you. It's it's it's so it's so real.
>> I started doing taekwond do. stopped
because my sensei was being an [ __ ]
But I did do some taekwondo and then I
ended up in an altercation and I was so
proud of myself because when the
altercated I was ABLE TO LIKE STAND ON
MY OWN too [laughter]
>> and that man looked back at me LIKE OH
SHE DIDN'T BUDGE NO [ __ ] OFF ME
>> right
[laughter] and it's that confidence like
we are and I think that's what you know
what Pluto and Aquarius I think when we
initially even connected was Saturn And
Aquarius, you were one of the people who
had reposted my video about chat [ __ ]
get banged and that made it go viral,
right? And then Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> I was insistent. IT MADE ME GO VIRAL.
>> AND SO even so to me even
>> by the way I used to run and be like
like [laughter]
>> I was not someone saying why is she
running? I was saying how cuz I can run
for five feet and I'm like it's done.
>> No. and and I would need to run and be
by the water and do all of these things
because it's my reminder that I'm here.
>> What's your big three?
>> Where what's your big three? What are
your signs? Like what's your
>> Oh, I love that you're asking this, not
you asking AND NOT ME. [laughter] SO,
I'M a Libra sun, Scorpio moon, allegedly
Sagittarius rising. I used to think I
was an Aries rising, but I'm not. I'm
Sagittarius rising. I had to do my own
birthtime rectification cuz I practice
astrology as well.
>> Right. You would think so, but actually
Sagittarius the archer makes sense. And
the filthy the way that I like to swear
up and down sag [laughter]
because I'm a Cancer Cancer Virgo. So
when you said water, I was like I mean I
have to be I have found that like water
is really
>> that girl for me. I've started swimming
again and it is it's now become like I I
felt it when I couldn't swim cuz it was
a snowstorm and they had closed the YMCA
and my body was like what's the plan?
>> Yeah,
>> we going in the tub. What we doing?
>> What's the plan?
>> Yeah, we have to do something. Wow. No,
I'm really glad we got to do this and I
hope that I know that we'll do this
again but we we want to do it soon. So
the the how is that be? sort it out cuz
we've got so much more to discuss.
Especially our books. This is just THE
TIP OF THE ICEBERG. It was like an
introduction to each other and official.
[laughter]
>> It was y'all basically watched the
FaceTime.
>> That's essentially what you watched.
This was FaceTime that you got to
witness
>> because what I would really love to at
some point even delve into more is how
you mentioned about your mom earlier and
I think about my experience with my mom
and just just for the general term about
the mother wound. Right. Right.
mother wounds. Yeah. And and and and how
that leads us towards this path of
social justice or whatever or advocacy,
however you want to see it. There's
something about um parenting ourselves
and then seeing that thing in other
people and in the world and saying, "I
want other people to experience this
journey." Not that I'm doing it for
them. I just want them to experience
coming home to and holding the little
girl inside. And and whenever I think
about, well, why am I doing this? Who am
I doing this for? Because that girl had
to go through so much and felt so
unprotected in a very very challenging
world. And and I want her to see that
things get better because I helped make
it so.
>> I know. You just [laughter]
>> Yes.
>> Cheers. Cheers.
>> Cheers.
>> [laughter]
>> just saying
>> t is good actually. Tal love. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Um that right there.
>> I will say this. Even though I didn't
put out the memoir, writing the memoir
brought me there. Mhm.
>> It It took me It got me over mountains
and through streams that I don't know
that I necessarily would have traveled
at this point in my life, like just in
traditional therapy, but in really
exploring
um my relationship with codependency.
Um, you know, looking at my decisions
and my choices, it was like, why do you
do these decisions over here? Why do you
make them so well? But then over here,
>> that was like me in relationships and
friendship.
>> Oh, I was getting there. Yes.
Relationship. Yeah. Yeah. Smart woman,
dumb girl. That's us.
>> Smart woman, dumb girl. Because we've
been we have been lauded for our
achievements. Um, you're Nigerian, so I
know that you have been lauded for your
achievements. [laughter]
>> My mom leads with that. She leads with
that. Yeah,
>> she's in the honor society. She has been
doing the things.
>> Do you know who my daughter is?
>> Do Do you know? [laughter]
>> I'll be like, "Mom, please."
>> I know what it is. My mother's from
Grenada. It's very that Well, you know,
she has a masters from Columbia
University. It's not like she just come
and just throwing around, man. really
smart mans mind man you could write you
could write mans and like you need that
you need that however what you didn't
get was
>> I hear you
>> you're scared
>> let's talk about it
>> like
>> and what's nuts is that we were so
intellectual about our emotions
>> that we knew that what we were feeling
was legit
>> and it was not being corroborated
and it made us feel abandoned and it
made us feel crazy. And then we grew up
and we sought out relationships with
people who would make us feel like we
weren't abandoned and then they would
turn around and make us feel crazy and
it was like [screaming]
[laughter]
>> and so now I have five cats and that's
right now [laughter]
>> I have five cats and a dog and I haven't
had sex in two and a half years.
>> That's crazy cuz I'm going on to a year.
I've got my sun and my plants and and
you know I I feel the best I've ever
felt. You know, I feel
>> someone asked me to do my skin regimen
recently and I was like I'm single.
>> That's no nobody's troubling me, right?
>> And and because of the how because of
the way our brains work
>> and nobody's troubling me that's not
working on themselves,
>> right?
>> I have a little bit of grace for you if
I know that you're trying.
>> A little bit of grace. A little bit. And
for me ultimately because of the way
that our brain works where we're trying
where we break down what's happening in
society like we are really great
observers right and doers. So somebody
being in our in our realm, right? I'm
going to try and understand what is
this? Who are you? What's going on here?
That when that person isn't even trying
to understand themselves like that, what
am I doing? What the hell am I doing?
And then it's like, oh, I asking it's
not that deep.
>> It is that deep.
>> It's very deep, but I guess you know a
spoonful of water would feel deep to
you. So don't worry about it. That's
where the truth That's where the truth
translator messes with people because
they're like, "Quit translating my
spoonful of water.
>> Stop doing that. Leave it alone. Leave
it alone about society. I I find you so
sexy when you're talking about society
and all of the things that are going on.
Don't turn that lens that you have, that
laser-like lens. Don't turn it on me.
But I'm only doing what I would do for
myself. The reason the reason we are
where we are is because I've had to sit
with myself at some some of the most
harrowing moments of my life and just
say, "Girl, what's going on? What's
going on?
>> How did we get here?
>> How was social? How did
>> how did we get here? [laughter]
>> How did we get here?" [laughter]
>> Nobody.
>> Especially not. nut. No, I had no
business being there but owning it. I
had no business being there, but here I
am. What is the lesson?
>> I'll never forget when I called my own
girl and was like,
>> you know, so I had sent um I sent Baldi
um $500 for bail, but then his best
friend had hit me up for another 500
saying that I hadn't paid enough. And to
be to be honest, I don't even know if he
really got locked up. And so she let me
finish my story and she was real quiet
and she went
Girl, why are you in this situation?
[laughter]
>> You know when the tone is so soft?
[laughter] Because the truth is so hard.
>> Yes.
>> Cuz literally, what are you doing?
>> Why is this even a scenario that you're
in? [clears throat]
>> What are we talking about right now?
Because if we saw this in the sitcom, oh
>> oh,
>> we would be like, oh be like
typing.
>> She is so so Oh my god. How did she not
know that? That is so silly. Anybody can
see that from a mile away.
>> Yeah, here an inch away. Just
>> just oblivious.
>> What? So, you know, it's it's a it's a
journey and um like you said, being able
to hold that inner child The to me the
loneliness is really your inner child.
That's the loneliness we feel is that
inner child not feeling seen. And I
remember reaching a point where I was
like like hold
>> I think I healed my inner child. Y'all
>> I think I like myself. There was a day
that I was just like yo I think I I like
I like myself.
>> Like I don't feel lonely anymore. I just
feel solitude. Like sometimes I'm just
like
>> I was lost for 5 days this week because
there was a snowstorm and I was fine.
>> It's it's beautiful. I relish my own
company. So some days when I've dropped
my son off at school, I can't wait to
get home, not go gym, not do any just go
home and just be by myself, you know,
just just enjoy me. I think the other
day I was packing cuz I do these um
spiritual bath salts and I was packing
up the orders. I had no music on. I had
no TV on and I was just like I love it.
Oh, this is so I just there was
something
>> similar experience
[laughter]
>> because the other day I literally was
like
>> let's do no TV.
>> Let's just cuz I was doing graphic
design for um a drop that I'm about to
put out called um How Black Am I Going
to Have to Get
>> and [laughter]
>> I like
>> and I was I was like let's do no TV. And
then I was trying to find like music to
play or or um a book to listen to. And
then I was like, "No, let's just just do
this." And I was just there in silence.
Like when I draw, my favorite way to
draw is really just in silence.
>> Wow.
>> And you're so multi-talented. I
>> I just love it. You know, like seeing
somebody else and saying things that
people say to you and you're just like,
"Wow, this is so cool. [laughter]
I mean,
all of the things.
>> It's really um but but you know, I was
thinking the other day
>> about people like us, right? Where we're
in the forest. We're all connected.
>> Yeah. I was about
>> right in the mcelium. What are we how
are we showing up in the mcelium? And
>> I always think of myself as a mangrove
tree. Oh, and I think
>> if you think about a mangrove tree, like
the roots are exposed and you can see
all the roots. And I feel like the
reason I see myself as a mangrove tree
is because as a multi-hyphenate creative
like all of my art forms are the method
through which I am nurturing and working
to decolonize folks and like none of
them can be hidden. They need to all be
in motion, right? So, so sometimes
people are like, "Oh my god, it seems
like you have a lot going on."
>> Cuz I do. [laughter]
>> I do. I do. We do have a lot going on.
>> Yes.
>> There's a lot going on in here and here.
>> Yes. Yeah. All of it. All of it. I was
like, you know what? I think I'm going
to do a mixtape.
>> Why not?
>> I was like,
and I need to figure out a title.
[laughter] And it's like, but Amanda,
you're also doing da da da da. And it's
like, yeah, it's yeah, WHY NOT?
>> THERE'S NO THERE'S NO timeline on it.
It's just
>> it's another thing and it's and it's
because we are tapped in. You talk about
the mycelidium network that we are
vessels through which life wants to
experience itself. So when we think
about these are I've just had this
random idea that I want to do this
thing. No, no, it's it's what wants to
be birthed into the world and it said
hey do you want to be my vessel? AND
WE'VE GONE, YEAH, why not? How about it?
I'LL DO THAT. Why not?
[laughter]
>> I'm the vessel in it.
>> Yeah, I'm the vessel in it.
I'm not. So when people like, "Oh, you
act, you've got the pole dance studio,
you do this, you write. How do how do
they all go together?" Me, they go
together cuz me, I'm the one doing all
of the things. They're just an different
expressions of me and my explorations of
what it is to be liberated in this life.
>> Yes.
>> It's going to take It's not
>> Yeah.
>> It's not about like people think of it
as like, "How do you balance?" I'm like,
"I'm not trying to balance. I still need
things to be in harmony, you know,
>> and and the universe is chaotic as
people like to call it. It's it just is.
It's beautiful because it just is. And
you should never rely on, oh, tomorrow
I'm hoping to see the same Amanda and
I'm hoping to see the same thing. You
should be open to the idea that you're
going to see me tomorrow and I'll be
doing something
be doing something.
>> Was like, I liked your hair better,
Curly Blocked. Oh, because who are
also recognized?
>> I had curly hair for 40 YEARS. CAN I
LIVE?
>> CAN I? CAN I? YES, she can.
>> Yes.
>> You know how much time I've gotten back
also
>> by having locks?
>> Oh, you
not us lock sisters.
>> I wake up and I'm ready to go. Something
about locks. I want you to know is that
you always look cool.
>> Always. always. It's I just love it so
much.
>> Even if I just tie it up [laughter]
>> she's liberated. She's bohemian. You
know, it's just it always it's always
>> and there's a beauty in that as well.
There's a beauty in just moving how we
want to move and and my locks have been
a major part of that journey as well.
And at times it's tough cuz you're
breaking away from what the ideological
stance is around beauty, right? and and
how everybody or a lot of people are
moving and the and the ones who are
deemed attractive, right? Um or
conventionally so and still being like,
"But I'm a hot girl. Are you crazy?"
Like, [laughter]
>> never have I felt more sexy than when
I've had my locks. Cuz I'm like, I this
is me. Like, I'm just doing me. No, look
at us, man. Oh, no. Thank you, Amanda.
me. You see me? You see me? Thank you so
much. I'm so glad that we did this and
we started the ball rolling, right?
Because that was the other thing, too,
y'all. When we decided to do this, it
wasn't like, "All right, well, I'll talk
to you in March." It was like, "What are
you doing on Friday?" Like, "Let's go.
Let's go. While the momentum is here,
whilst all of the things are happening
in Aquarius, let's go now. Now, now
there's something about it." And I think
that this is the beginning of so much.
And and
you know I keep thinking about what we
said about mycelium and it's having that
connection having that network cuz as
you say we see the manifestation of the
mycelium above ground right but the
network continues underneath and who
knows how these interconnectivities are
going to work and how they're going to
show themselves in the future but we're
seeing each other and and I think the
time is now. I think we model, you know,
not in a pedestal way, but we are here
to model what it is to say, I I feel at
home in myself and let me connect with
other people and then we have a home
that we can all live in connectively um
you know in the outer world.
You're great, man.
>> Same. [laughter]
Ditto.
>> So, the next thing that we need to do is
get to Grenada. Operation get to
Grenada.
>> [laughter]
>> Operation Get to Greens.
>> Yes. I can't wait. I can't wait. No, I
appreciate you and thank you No, thank
you for um um honoring me with your time
and your vulnerability. Just all of the
things that just make you the wonderful
person that you are as you forge ahead
with all of the things that you're
doing. And you know, we see each other
and we'll continue. We'll continue
disrupting the things.
>> Yes, ma'am.
I know. I know. It was proper juicy. It
was like watching a FaceTime of two
Babs. And to think I was in a freaking
horrific mood today because somebody had
like reached out to me who said that
they were, you know, they've loved my
content. They've listened to me for
years and they wanted to donate some um
things that they no longer needed in
their apartment. They wanted to donate
it to the children's home. They don't
want anything in return. So, I paid £200
to book um the shipper guy that takes
that picks up things for me so they can
be shipped to Lagos, Nigeria. I paid the
guy £200 in this Rasclar economy, in
this cozy lives, I paid the guys um set
off to go and pick up the things. The
guy's not answering the phone. Not
answering the phone, not answering
messages after messaging me up till
10:00 p.m. last night saying, "Oh, all
of the things are boxed, ready for you
to come and get." Now, ignoring
messages. I I imagine probably even
blocked me so well blocked probably on
WhatsApp. I don't know why cuz I was
like, "Yeah, we'll take this. We'll take
that. Thank you so much." At one point
they he even said to me, "Stop thanking
me. I just want to get it sorted." So
even the the energy was a bit weird. And
this is why I don't like to get familiar
with people and people might think, "Oh,
why isn't why hasn't Kleti connected
with me?" Because I don't know if you're
going to be a weirdo.
So, even off this thing of I want to
donate these things. If I don't hear
from you within 24 hours, I'm going to
put the flyer out so people can come and
get the things. I messaged back 5 days
later. Only one item had gone. And I
said, "Oh, that's a blessing. Yeah, I'll
take the rest of the things. That will
be wonderful. Thank you so much." So, we
were organizing the logistics, bearing
in mind that I'm a really busy person.
So, I've organized the shipper, paid the
deposit for the shipper, cuz there's so
much more money to pay. It's not just
£200. I've got to pay like quite a lot
of money once it finally gets to [ __ ]
So, I've paid I've done this. I've asked
for my brother to go and be there. And I
think part of it was that he was
expecting me to come, but I said my
brother was going to come on um you
know, on my behalf cuz I had so much to
do like this interview today. So, I
wasn't going to make it, but my brother
was going to be, you know, doing all of
that. He knew well ahead of time. Then
he started sending very weird cryptic
messages like, "Oh, I hope you know that
I don't want to have to chat to anyone.
I don't want to have to do this." Um, so
it has to be people that you trust cuz I
don't want I just want to pack the
boxes. I don't want to be involved. Calm
down. I've already said it's fine.
What's going on? What's going on?
Only to now for it to get to the day the
ship has headed over there and ignoring
calls, ignoring messages. It will never
be well with you. Anything that you
touch is going to turn to dust. You
silly [ __ ] I just needed to say
that because the children's home is my
absolute heart. And when people do
things like this, weird [ __ ] like this,
it blows my mind and it breaks my heart
because we've been at this, bear in
mind, for 5 days trying to sort out the
logistics
and then only to start ignoring calls
after you message up to 10 p.m. last
night going, "Yeah, I'm done boxing for
now, but pretty much most of it is
ready, sending me pictures, pictures,
and it gets to the day. You know the
time that the ship is coming." So I'm
like, is it an elaborate prank? Is this
a scheme that Todd set up?
I don't even know. But I think
everything happens as it should and I'm
protected by the Most High. And we've
still had so many wonderful donations.
One of my clients who I did a tarot
reading for, I read for her um rather
regularly, but whenever I read for her,
she buys me a gift. So the last time I
read for her, after my reading with her,
um she got me a gift card so I could get
new Vibram Five Fingers. You know the
five finger shoes, the running shoes
that I wear that some of you call ugly.
You need to mind your tone, mind your
voices. Okay, mind your words. Um, she
bought me a gift card so I could buy new
running shoes, which was super cute.
Then this time round I had um I read for
her and she said, you know, I want to
give you a gift as always. Bearing in
mind she pays for the readings. So it's
not like I'm reading for her for free.
She paid for the readings, then she gets
me a gift thereafter. I mean, other
people do, too. Thank you for my French
bloom. Thank you for my earrings. Thank
you for all of the things, my massages.
All of you lot that get me wonderful
things. I appreciate you. So, she
messages and she's like, I want to get
you a gift. Would you prefer I donate to
the children's home or would you prefer
that I buy a bunch of your books and I
give it out over here? And I said, I'd
really appreciate donation to the
children's home because otherwise I'm
paying out of pocket for a lot of things
cuz the donations don't always cover it.
although so many of you have been kind
to now offer to pay the school fees for
the children. Um so I really appreciate
that. Um so I said yeah you can make a
donation to the children's home and she
made a donation of £333 cuz she knows I
like repetitive numbers and it really
really touched me. The reason I say that
is cuz there are so many people who have
shown me kindness throughout the years.
And this incident with this person won't
taint that, but it did hurt my feelings
today. And I arrived here um ready to
record, but I was in a bit of a foul
mood. But the moment I saw Brent, of
course, BUT THE BECAUSE I KNOW BRENT WAS
LIKE, BUT THE MOMENT I SAW AMANDA on
screen as well, I don't know what it
was, it just brightened me up because it
reminded me that I'm not alone and I've
been doing this for years and people
have said so many [ __ ] things about
me throughout the years and it has felt
lonely, right? But I've, you know, risen
above it and I've continued on my way
and I've continued to be sexy. You know,
I thought I'd throw that in there. But,
you know, I've continued doing my thing.
So it makes me glad when I see another
person who's been having a similar
experience just on another side, the
other side of the pond in another
country. It's great to be able to
connect in that way and just to have
that reminder that we don't do any of
this stuff alone. Like we all have to
have each other and we are in that
forest and you know Amanda makes a great
point. What kind of tree are you in this
forest that we're in? And I'm still
trying to figure that out. So um thank
you all for listening. Thank you for
joining me. It's been me, Kletchi, the
baby girl, aka Mother of London, and
this has been Front Page [ __ ] where
we turn bad news into good conversation.
So, yeah. Um, follow, support, do all of
the things. The bath salts have pretty
much run out, but I might do another
drop in a in a few weeks cuz it takes
quite a lot of energy from me to make
them and for them to work for you when
you use them. Um, but yeah, I guess
that's it. Definitely comment.
Definitely if you know that you've got
the funds to do so, make the event with
myself and Amanda happen. I was thinking
of doing a live show in October to
celebrate my birthday. If you also want
to fund that, go right ahead. But don't
disappear at the last minute cuz I'll
curse you, too. But no, let me stop now.
I'll catch you on the other side of the
news. Peace.
[music] Have you heard the news? It's
probably been twisted.
>> [music]
>> To keep the general population
conflicted,
better lick your finger and turn the
[music and singing] page.
Dissect the lines that page you to rage.
[music]
Get out of your one day.
Turn [singing] up the volume on front
page [ __ ] [music]
Yeah.